What would I need to change about my
body to survive in space like a
tardigrade? The moment you step out of a
spaceship, you wouldn't immediately
freeze or explode. But, the lower
pressure outside your body would
immediately cause all of the air to
rush out of you. And that same lower
pressure would lower the boiling point
of water, so that water in your eyes
starts to boil.
Our tardigrade friend solves that
problem by dehydrating itself, squeezing
out 97%
of its water and curling up into a
little husk. Their metabolism drops to
0.01%
of normal. Uh-oh, bad news. If you're in
the sun, that side of your body is
heating up to about 150° C, and the
other side of your body is freezing.
But, tardigrades flood their cells with
a special protein that turns remaining
liquid into [music] glass, protecting
them from these extreme temperatures.
But now, radiation is turning my DNA to
shreds. But, tardigrades can survive a
thousand times the radiation that would
kill you or me because it makes a
special protein cleverly called the
damage suppressor that wraps around its
DNA like armor. And we've tested this
protein in humans, and DNA damage fell.
And in 2007, scientists opened a
container of 3,000 tardigrades in space,
and most of them survived. Because the
second they touch water, they just
And right now, there are live
tardigrades on the moon. To see why,
subscribe.